World War I Poster Collection, circa 1914-1918
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
World War I Poster Collection, circa 1914-1918
MS 526
University of Arizona. Library. Special Collections
This is an artificial collection comprised of posters relating to World War I with materials originating from the United States, Canada, France, and Great Britain.
8 Linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
At the beginning of the 20th century, the poster was the primary instrument for mass communication. The poster was accepted and immediately understood by the masses and was cheap to manufacture. Posters from the First World War (28 July 1914-11 November 1918) were created to appeal to people's basic conscious or subconscious emotions of self-preservation, patriotic pride, and moral traditions. These posters had a modern look and employed familiar ideas and images as well as a simplified view of war as right versus wrong. Posters used various methods to convey their intended messages including using images of national leaders past or present or quotations from these leaders, symbols, slogans, myths allegories, and metaphors, and semiotic illustration.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 2 series.
Series I: United States Posters circa 1914-1918
Series II: International Posters circa 1914-1918
Scope and Content Note
This is an artificial collection that has two series and is comprised of posters relating to World War I. Most of the posters held in this collection are one-sheet in size (27"x41"). Many are regarding enlistment and monetary contributions to the war effort in the United States, Canada, Great Britain and France. The first series contains materials from the United States with the second series containing materials from Canada, France, and Great Britain. The collection consists of broadsides comprised primarily of text and graphic works by anonymous and well-known artists, including James Montgomery Flagg and Joseph Pennell. The majority of the posters are in English, with some posters in French.
Access Terms
Flagg, James Montgomery, 1877-1960.
Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Posters.
World War, 1914-1918 -- United States.
World War, 1914-1918 -- France.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Great Britan.
Container List
- Series 1: United States Posters, circa 1914-1918
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the artists' last name.
  - Armstrong, Rolf, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Ashe, M., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Ernest Hamlin (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Baldridge, Cyrus LeRoy (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Barclay, McClelland, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Benda, Wladyslaw T. (2 posters; one is a Polish Army recruiting poster), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Beneker, Gerrit (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Bracker, M. Leone, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Arthur William, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Bull, Charles Livingston, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Cesare, Oscar, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Christy, Howard Chandler (4 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Coffin, Haskell, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Colen, Arthur William, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Coughlin, John A., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Crepaux, Fernand A., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Daugherty, James H., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, Casper, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Falls, Charles B. (4 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Fisher, Harrison, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Flagg, James Montgomery (6 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Foringer, A.E., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Forsythe, Vic, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Giles, H., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Grant, T. Gordon, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Groesbeck, Dan Sayre, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - H., J.M. (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Harrison, Laurence, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Herter, Albert (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Homer, Winslow, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Ickes, John W., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Ingres, Maurice, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Lentz, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Leyendecker, J.C. (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Lynch, Vincent, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Moore, Bruce, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Norton, John, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Nuyttens, J.P., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Orr, Alfred Everitt (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Paus, Herbert (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Pennell, Joseph, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Raleigh, Henry, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Rice, Burton, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Riesenberg, Sidney H. (4 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Roberts, Hazel, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - St. John, J. Allen, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Shafer, L.A. (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Sheridan, John E., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Dan (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Spear, Fred, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Spear, Gill, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Sterner, Albert (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Stevens, W.D., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Strothmann, F., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Treidler, Adolph (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Underwood, Clarence (2 posters; 2 copies of one), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Verress, J. Paul, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Whitehead, Walter, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Williams, J. Scott, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Woolf, Samuel J., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Young, Ellsworth, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified (24 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Czechoslovakian Recruiting Posters (2 posters; School of Printing and Graphic Arts, Wentworth Institute, Boston, MA), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
- Series 2: International Posters Posters, circa 1914-1918
  This series is arranged alphabetically by country and contains two different series of Canadian WP posters, British Parliamentary Recruiting Committee posters, and French posters. Posters are in English and French.
  - Canadian Poster WP #1, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #2, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #3, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #4, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #5, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #6, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #7, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #8, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #9, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #10, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #11, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #12, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #1, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #2, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #3, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #4, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #5, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Poster WP #6, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - France – Besnard, Paul Albert, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Capon, G., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Cappiello, Loenetto, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Carlu, Jacques, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Droit, Jean (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Faivre, Jules Abel (4 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Falter, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Hansi (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Jonas, L. (2 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Leroux, Auguste, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Loring, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Poulbot, Francesque, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Poulbot, Francesque, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Redon, Georges, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Scott, Georges, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Sem, pseud. (Coursat, Georges) (3 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Simay, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Steinlen, Theophile Alexandre (5 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - France – Unidentified (5 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #22, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #32, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #49, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #52, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #55, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster (Wardle, Arthur) #58, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #62, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #64, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #66, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #69, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #72, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #78, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #80, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #85C, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #94, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #96 (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #98, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #99, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #104 (2 copies), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster (Partridge, Bernard) #111, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #113, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #116, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster (Wood, Gerald) #118, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary Recruiting Committee poster #123, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Unnumbered Parliamentary Recruiting Committee posters (3 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Great Britain – Brangwyn, Frank, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 4)
  - Great Britain – Lipscombe, Guy, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 4)
  - Great Britain – Pollex, V.C., circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 4)
  - Great Britain – Unidentified (3 posters), circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 4)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #2, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #3, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #4, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #5, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #6, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #8, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #9, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #10, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #12, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #13, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #14, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #15, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #17, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #19, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #20, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #21, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #22, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Great Britain – Parliamentary War Savings Committee posters #23, circa 1914-1918 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)